

Adrián Hinojosa Calleja, PhD

Data Scientist

Barcelona - 611 03 31 20 - hinojosa.a@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/adhinojosa hinojosaad.github.io

A Data Scientist and PhD Mathematics, specializes in Probability & Statistics. Experience with Machine Learning, Time Series Forecasting, and Gaussian Noises Analysis. +10 years teaching Mathematics.

Educational Background

PhD Mathematics

Universitat de Barcelona, 2022 Cum Laude

Master Mathematical Sciences

TU Berlin, Germany, 2016

Degree Mathematics

UNAM, Mexico, 2013 Graduated with honors

Certificates

Data Science with Python

Barcelona Activa, 2022

Introduction to Functional Data Analysis with R

UAB, 2018

Technical Skills

- Python
- R
- SQL
- Power BI
- Java

Soft Skills

- Problem resolution
- Critical thinking
- Teamwork
- Leadership

Work Experience

Predoctoral Researcher

Universitat de Barcelona April 2017 to January 2022 Researcher in Stochastic Partial Differential Equations.

Teacher's assistant of Probability and Statistics courses.

Mathematics Teacher

Logos Middle School

August 2012 to June 2014

Teacher of Mathematics I and III courses.

Organization Experience

Organizer

Barcelona's Probability Seminar January 2021 to March 2022

Member of the Executive Board

Institut de Matematiques de la Universitat de Barcelona *November 2017 to January 2022*

Projects

Decathlon IT Academy Hackathon, 2022

1st place. Classification model which predicts if a client will buy or not an available product on a webpage.

Barcelona Air, 2022

Time Series Analysis of pollution concentrations in a neighborhood of Barcelona.

Space X, 2022

3rd Place in the Talent Squad-Data Science Challenge. Classification model to predict the states of turbulence from a space rocket.